That Cui Wenkui won't listen to reason.
He really pisses me off.
He is a man of ambition.
It's just a pity his ambition is misplaced.
I should have just knocked him out earlier
and carried him out.
But your criticism in the prison was spot on.
What you said was very insightful.
It hit the nail on the head.
I just say whatever comes to mind.
It's rare that you would actually praise me.
I will keep it in mind.
Don't just say nice things.
I want action.
Look at you.
I just praised you for making progress,
and you went back to your true colors immediately.
I haven't even said what I want.
How do you know I went back to my true colors?
Okay, tell me.
I want you to take me with you
on every mission.
I want to make progress with you.
No problem.
I can promise you.
Except for special missions,
I will take you with me.
It's a deal then.
It's a deal.
I don't think either of you made any progress.
You both have to write a self-criticism.
Aren't you in charge of the guerrilla?
How come you have time to come out?
Secretary Peng Tao from the West Henan Special Committee is here.
He wants to see you.
Secretary Peng is here?
Let's go.
Let's go see him.
Secretary Peng, have some water.
They should be back soon, Secretary Peng.
Baozi, this is our Secretary Peng Tao.
This is Comrade Cai Baozi.
Secretary Peng, we've finally been looking forward to you.
Hello.
Hello, Comrade Cai Baozi.
Please sit.
Come, let's sit.
Comrade Cai Baozi,
you've been in Sandaoyuan for so long,
and this is our first time meeting.
But your name
is well-known to me.
Blowing up the Qinglong Mountain Fortress
and attacking the Japanese transport trucks.
You did a great job.
None of the comrades in the Eighth Route Army Office
doesn't know you.
You flatter me.
Since Shanzhou City fell,
we lost contact with the party organization.
Under the leadership of Comrade Cui Wenpei,
we organized the scattered swordsmen
and spontaneously organized anti-Japanese activities.
But without the guidance of the party organization,
we just rely on our personal experience
and mess around
without a clear direction.
Good job.
Now,
the Japanese stopped at Hanguguan.
It is said that their logistics supply line cannot keep up.
This is
thanks to you.
Moreover, Qinglong Village guards the main roads on three sides.
With your actions,
the Japanese have lost
substantial control over the counties.
The guerrilla forces below
can fight so well.
We still need Secretary Peng's guidance.
Who is this girl?
Shangguan Ying from Qinglong Village.
You are Shangguan Bao's daughter.
You truly are the fierce daughter of a hero.
You flatter me.
What do you say?
Are you willing to join the Eighth Route Army
and fight the Japanese with us?
I am.
As long as I'm with Baozi,
I'm willing to do anything.
This girl is very sincere to you.
Don't let her down.
Yes, Secretary.
The war of resistance is our priority now.
So we decided
to put our relationship on hold
until we drive out the Japanese.
Nonsense.
When did the organization ever say
you can't have a personal life while fighting the war?
The revolution also needs
to be passed down from generation to generation.
Comrade Secretary, I agreed to this.
My man must have great ambitions.
I just criticized him once,
and you're already defending him.
Incredible.
I really can't mess with you young couple.
This girl is nice. She knows how to care for her man.
Secretary Peng,
you risked your life coming to Sandaoyuan.
Is there any task you want to assign to us?
The comrades from the Eighth Route Army Office and I
have discussed it
and decided to officially establish
an armed force behind enemy lines in Sandaoyuan
to unite all anti-Japanese forces.
In Japanese-occupied, controlled, and adjacent areas,
by using scattered and mobile tactics,
we will strike the enemy
and cut off their transportation lines.
That's great.
We've finally waited for this day.
On behalf of the Eighth Route Army Office, I officially announce
the establishment of the Western Henan Anti-Japanese Independent Battalion.
Comrade Cai Baozi is appointed
as the captain of the Independent Battalion.
Comrade Cui Wenpei is appointed as the political commissar of the Independent Battalion,
specifically in charge of propaganda,
guerrilla warfare, and united front work in Sandaoyuan.
The two new comrades, Shangguan Ying and Yuanshangfei, are appointed
as the vice captains of the Independent Battalion,
responsible for assisting with your execution work.
Please rest assured.
We promise to complete the task.
Comrade Secretary,
since you appointed me as the vice captain,
I have something to report to you.
Sit down and talk.
Well, sit down.
Comrade Shangguan Ying is very bold.
A new broom sweeps clean.
Come, tell me.
What kind of work?
Cui Wenkui was framed by Zhang Gongyan.
We want to rescue him. Please approve it.
Yinger.
Tell me your reasons.
After arriving at Sandaoyuan, he was dedicated to resisting the Japanese.
He never bullies the common people.
As you said,
everything should focus on the big picture.
We need manpower for the resistance now.
A talent like him should be saved.
On the way here,
I also heard about this.
Although Cui Wenkui is in the National Army,
he has
killed enemies
and bled on the front lines.
Currently, the enemy is strong and we are weak.
Our united anti-Japanese forces
should include patriotic generals like Cui Wenkui.
It is exactly because of their existence
that our nation has hope.
If they die in vain,
it would be self-destruction.
Yes.
I will execute the rescue immediately.
I'll go with you.
Yes.
Brigadier Cui,
let's hit the road.
Didn't they say we'd leave in the afternoon?
It's not even noon yet.
The time has been changed. It's earlier.
Stop being vain.
When you get to Yama,
he won't care if you're dressed neatly.
Everyone gets fried in a cauldron of boiling oil.
If you go to the other side,
don't blame me.
I am just following orders.
What are you talking about?
The theater commander said there is no need for a trial.
Anyone who defects to the Communists and betrays the Party will be executed on the spot.
Bullshit.
Do you know how many times the headquarters
has awarded me the Medal of Loyalty and Valor?
Just because you tell the Party and the State that I defected,
does that mean I actually did?
Look closely.
Black and white with a red seal.
I wouldn't dare forge it.
Even if I had the guts,
I wouldn't dare fake it.
I originally thought
the Theater Commander would at least give you a symbolic trial.
But before we even set out today,
he sent someone with the verdict.
It seems his determination to kill you
is even stronger than mine.
Cui Wenkui.
I don't actually want to kill you.
I was still counting on you
to help me hold the last position
at Sandaoyuan.
But you,
you're just too stubborn to understand.
Have you figured it out yet?
All these years,
not only have you failed to get promoted,
you've also lost your life.
Think about it.
Do I have the power
to swallow all those military supplies and pay by myself?
I'll tell you the truth.
The Theater Command is full of big tigers.
Every single one of them has an appetite
bigger than mine.
And you are so stubborn.
Commander.
I advised you several times, but you wouldn't listen.
You refuse to get on the bus,
and you won't let others get on either.
If they don't kill you, who will they kill?
Cui Wenkui.
Male, 29 years old.
From Peiping.
Currently residing in Shanzhou.
Charge of colluding with the Communists and treason.
Executed on the spot.
I fought to the death for the party and the country,
and you're going to kill me over this, huh?
Cui Wenkui.
The Japanese are so powerful now.
Everyone is trying to find a way out,
only fools like you would charge forward.
Men, take him away!
Go.
Don't touch me with your dirty hands.
Thank you for speaking up for my brother earlier.
I only said what everyone wanted to say.
Your brother cannot die.
And these days,
you should know me.
I am a straightforward person,
and I can't keep anything to myself.
Secretary Peng agreed.
So my brother has hope.
I will definitely remember this favor.
I'm just worried
that your brother is too stubborn.
I'm afraid it will be like last time,
and we will make a wasted trip.
I'll tie him up and take him away if I have to.
I can't lose my brother no matter what.
With your words,
we can act without hesitation.
There's not much time left.
Don't worry too much.
In these mountains,
our swordsmen are faster than leopards.
Brothers, let's pick up the pace.
A life is at stake.
Yes, yes, yes.
Get up. Let's go.
Cui Wenkui.
You are exactly like your father.
Back then, your father refused to accept our bribes
and went to the Nanjing government to report us
for extorting wealth and bleeding the people dry.
As a result,
we got rid of him.
Now you're blocking our way to wealth
and refusing to accept our reorganization obediently.
As a result, we're executing you too.
Why are you father and son
so stubborn?
Are you saying
that my father
was killed by you?
That's right, we killed him.
Your father was the deputy mayor of Beiping.
Who would dare to kill him openly?
After I got rid of him,
I had it publicized in the newspapers,
claiming it was retaliation by the Communists.
And everyone believed it.
Beat him.
I've said what I needed to say.
Just accept your fate
and die knowing the truth.
Consider this
my last act of comradeship to you.
Prepare for execution.
Zhang Gongyan.
I won't let you off even as a ghost.
I will tear you to pieces!
Ready.
Brigade Commander.
Brother.
Brigade Commander, go!
Untie him.
Go!
Give me the gun. Go!
Brigade Commander, go! Hurry!
Go! Go! Go!
Brothers, retreat!
Retreat!
Go!
Commander.
Cui Wenkui and the swordsmen have all run away.
Should we still pursue them?
Nonsense!
If we don't pursue them,
how will we explain this to the headquarters?
If our embezzlement of military pay is exposed,
we will spend the rest of our lives
in prison.
Go.
Yes, sir.
Brothers, after them!
Go!
Stay close behind.
Keep up, hurry.
Hurry, hurry.
Hurry.
Take a break, take a break.
Slow down, slow down.
Sit here.
Everyone, take a break here.
The pursuers are gone.
We are safe for now.
Brother, are you alright?
Everyone.
Words cannot express my gratitude.
If you ever need my help in the future,
I will gladly risk my life for you.
Don't say that.
Cui Wenkui,
join our guerrilla forces.
Miss Shangguan.
I am disheartened now
and don't want to join any organization.
Please understand.
Then what are your plans next?
I'm thinking of
pulling my independent brigade out first
and forming a separate anti-Japanese column.
But don't worry.
I will only fight the Japanese like before.
I won't get involved in anything else.
That's not a bad idea.
We can watch each other's backs
and support each other.
There are advantages to not being together.
Yes.
Let's go then.
Let's go find your troops.
Wenpei,
Before I pull my troops out,
I have to do something for our Cui family.
Listen up, troops at all checkpoints.
We must block Cui Wenkui's escape route.
He might be heading to the Communists.
Deploy a regiment of troops
on his inevitable path,
equipped with heavy weapons.
Eliminate him on his way back
and send him to meet his dead father.
Are you looking for me?
You!
Guards!
Stop shouting.
Those cowards
have already surrendered.
Commander Zhang.
You told me such a huge secret,
did you think I wouldn't come for you?
Wenkui.
Don't kill me.
Spare me.
I didn't want to kill your father either.
It's just that...
If I didn't kill him,
they would have killed me.
So
you killed my father
and framed the Communists for it?
And you kept this hidden from me
for twenty whole years?
Wenkui.
Spare me,
for the sake of
working together in the National Army.
Please spare me.
The party and state.
When the party and state escorted me to the execution ground
to kill me,
my devotion to them died.
A country with scums like you.
If you can't stabilize the country from within,
or defend against enemies from the outside,
the people will never live in peace and contentment.
Go down and apologize to my father.
Wen... Wenkui,
don't kill me.
I'll give you money.
I have US dollars.
I have gold bars.
Wenkui.
I'll burn this for you.
Brothers.
You've all followed me for over ten years.
Tell me,
do you still remember why you joined the army?
The warlords were fighting,
and the people were suffering.
Many brothers told me,
Brigade Commander,
I want to fight all over the map with you.
When the fighting is over,
then go home and reunite with our families.
I, Cui Wenkui, have kept these words in my heart
for over ten years.
But once the war started, it never ended.
The Central Plains War ended,
and then the Japanese invaded.
Many brothers were about to return home,
only to be sent back to the battlefield.
After fighting for so long,
sometimes I ask myself,
what keeps me going.
What's the reason?
I look back at the homeland behind me
and think of my family.
That is the reason we don't fear sacrifice
and keep holding on.
But when we're fighting on the front lines,
what are those high officials doing in the rear?
They are living in luxury and partying.
When they are in danger,
they will hand over our great country
without a fight.
Do we bleed and sacrifice for them?
Are the battles we fight
just to protect their power and status?
No.
Then are you still willing to follow such a government?
Exactly.
Such a government,
we can no longer follow.
We must be like the Communist Party
and fight the Japanese together.
Of course,
if any brothers want to go back,
here is some money.
Take it,
go back and reunite with your families.
Brigade Commander, we will follow you.
We will follow you.
Good.
You are all brave men.
From today on,
We are no longer the National Army.
We are the Sandaoyuan Anti-Japanese Independent Column.
Our father
worked for the Kuomintang his whole life.
Me too.
But in the end, it was all for nothing.
I didn't expect him to be killed by his own people.
I am even more ridiculous.
For the past twenty years,
I always thought the Communists did it.
Baozi.
About your father.
Wenkui,
what are you doing?
Sit down and talk.
Sit.
Here, drink some water.
Actually, this can't all be blamed on you.
It's all Zhang Gongyan's fault.
It's good that you woke up in time.
Everything can be remedied.
Let's put past grievances aside for now.
We brothers should fight the enemy together first.
That's the important thing.
Isn't there a saying,
brothers may quarrel at home, but they unite against outside threats.
You don't need to comfort me.
But don't worry, Baozi.
I will definitely fight bloody battles on the battlefield
to repay the kindness of you and your father.
All right, all right.
Let's not talk about this today.
The Japanese are planning to attack Hangu Pass now,
but their logistics are insufficient,
so they largely depend on cashing out the gold mine.
If they take Hangu Pass,
the entire Qinchuan will lose its barrier,
and will fall very soon.
In the end,
the gold mine is the crucial issue.
Baozi,
how about we do what you said,
and blow it up?
If blowing it up is the only way,
how do we do it? Who will do it?
What about the civilians inside?
Who will rescue them?
I will.
My team and I will go.
We will blow up the gold mine.
Wenkui, it really won't work.
As soon as you move out,
you will be spotted by the Japanese.
Even if you can fight your way in,
the Japanese around
will come from all directions to reinforce.
You won't be able to escape even if you blow it up.
You and your brothers
will all die inside.
It's not worth it.
Baozi, you know me.
As long as we can stop the Japanese,
I'm willing to die a thousand times.
We all admire your military spirit,
but what about the civilians inside?
Our difficulty now
is to blow up the gold mine
while ensuring their safety.
Right.
You Communists think this through more thoroughly.
But if so,
this mission will be even more daunting.
Isn't Uncle Liu in the mine?
If we can contact him,
we can coordinate from the inside and outside.
Blow up the mine
while he helps the civilians retreat.
That idea is workable.
The key is who should go.
How to get in and out?
If the message can't be sent out, it's useless.
Even if you're in a bad mood,
don't waste food.
I'll pick it up in a minute.
Why is fighting a war so difficult?
Worrying about this and that.
It makes us so timid.
What? Do you disagree with Wenpei's idea?
No.
I think she's right.
It's just that I can't help right now,
so I feel frustrated.
You play a big role too.
So many swordsmen
have united to fight Japan.
It's all thanks to your leadership.
Wenpei and I
don't have as much influence as you do.
But in the past,
everyone only looked out for themselves,
so it was simple and easy.
Now we have to think of others,
so we must be thorough.
But this problem
seems hard to solve.
Even you and Wenpei are out of ideas.
You're a vice-captain now.
Why are you so pessimistic?
The harder it is,
the more it shows your Baozi's capability.
If we only met simple problems,
I wouldn't feel a sense of achievement.
How else could I establish my authority
in front of you, my lady?
You want to establish your authority?
Miss, Baozi.
I just went out to scout
and ran into the Japs collecting grain in Dawang Town.
Guess who led the way for them?
Who?
Meng Shigui.
He's still alive?
He fled
when Chief Huo was fighting
Tahara Masao.
He hid at home for a while.
Then Tahara Masao found him,
and he started working for them.
Do you know where he is?
He lives in the detective squad compound in the county town.
It's not easy to make a move.
But I found out
that he often goes to the restaurant
with a bunch of his bad friends
and drinks until midnight before going back.
Let's go.
Where are you going?
Need you ask?
To get rid of that scum, of course.
Don't be reckless.
Let's discuss it first.
What's there to discuss?
He colluded with the Japs.
and harmed his own brothers.
Such a person deserves to die twice.
We can't touch the gold mine,
but we can still touch him.
Miss, Meng Shigui is inside.
Let's make our move.
There are too many people in the restaurant right now.
If we make a move, we might easily hurt others.
No rush.
Let's wait for him to come out.
Take the brothers and guard his retreat.
Go.
Yes.
Captain Meng.
The girls' songs here are pretty good, aren't they?
Not bad.
Let's continue drinking tomorrow.
I'm afraid I can't tomorrow.
I need to help the Imperial Army find a labor interpreter.
We'll come again another day.
Captain Meng, you are a busy man.
Let's meet up again in a few days.
Alright, see you.
See you.
Uncle Meng Si, hope you've been well.
M-
Miss.
I've been waiting for you for a long time
just to take your miserable life.
Miss,
it was all planned by Masao Tahara himself.
He forced me.
I didn't do it willingly.
Not willingly?
That uniform you're wearing
was exchanged for our brothers' lives.
I won't do it anymore.
I'll leave the detective squad right now.
I won't guide them anymore,
and I won't help them find a translator either.
It's too late.
For what you've done,
according to the rules of our swordsmen,
you should receive the punishment of three cuts and six holes.
But I have no time to waste on you,
so I'll just pierce right through your heart.
Miss!
I've let our brothers down.
I know I was wrong.
Save those words
for the brothers when you go down there.
Ying.
What?
He can't die yet.
We'll take him back first.
Miss, I'll go back with you.
Why did you bring him here?
Why didn't you kill this traitor?
Baozi said
we need to bring him back for questioning.
What's there to question?
He killed so many brothers in our stronghold.
Death by a thousand cuts wouldn't be enough.
If you can't do it,
let me.
Yuan.
Let me ask him a few questions first.
Then you can decide whether to kill him.
Boss Cai.
Meng Shigui,
do you want to live or die?
For my wife and children, I want to live.
Then answer my questions honestly.
Okay, I will.
Are you looking for a translator for the Japanese?
Yes.
The commoners in the gold mine
can't understand the Japanese technicians.
Accidents happen every day.
They need to find a translator.
So they gave this task to me.
You said you truly repented.
Is it true?
Yes.
Boss Cai, just give your orders.
Okay.
I want you to bring our people into the gold mine
and then bring them out safely.
Well...
The Japanese check very strictly.
They verify identities entering and exiting.
Do it or I'll kill you.
Okay. For my family,
I will do everything I can to get you in.
You really are a candle that won't light until lit.
Boss Huo was a prominent figure.
How could he trust a traitor like you?
I did it for my family too.
Meng Shigui.
We all know your background.
Whether you want to snitch or run,
the swordsmen of Sandaoyuan
will settle both old and new scores with you.
Understood.
Yuan, take him out.
Using Meng Shigui as a connection
to sneak our people in.
This is a good idea.
Leave the job of posing as a translator to me.
I still need someone to assist me
near the gold mine
to check out their defense layout.
I'll go with you.
I know a little Japanese.
It will definitely come in handy then.
You know Japanese?
How come you never mentioned it?
I just picked up a few phrases from others.
Baozi.
I know you are angry.
He does deserve to die.
But keeping him alive,
isn't that of great use?
Is there really no other way?
Do we have to use a traitor to help us?
To defeat the brutal Japanese devils,
it takes more than courage and determination.
It also takes this.
We must be good at creating all
opportunities to our advantage.
Keeping Meng Shigui as an inside man
makes it possible to blow up the gold mine.
The wealth your father left behind
won't be taken by the Japanese devils
and turned into weapons to kill our people.
If you think about it this way,
don't you think it has value?
Okay.
I'll spare his wretched life for now.
But if he betrays our brothers again
or harms the common people,
I will take his head immediately.
Rest assured.
With your imposing presence, Miss,
Meng Shigui will definitely behave.
However, since we already know
that he is a fence-sitter,
we will keep a close eye on him at all times
and give him no chance to act.
Baozi.
In this matter,
I hope you can forgive my impulsiveness.
I can't lose any more family members
or friends.
You won't.